<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-02T21:19:30-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">MicroSearch</title><entry><title type="html">A Wealth of Knowledge: Searching the Ivy League’s Videos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/a-wealth-of-knowledge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Wealth of Knowledge: Searching the Ivy League's Videos" /><published>2017-02-21T13:36:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-21T13:36:35-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/a-wealth-of-knowledge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/a-wealth-of-knowledge/">&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about YouTube, in my opinion, is the amount of videos available from colleges and universities around the world. If you haven’t seen this for yourself, I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=university+or+college&amp;amp;filters=channel&amp;amp;lclk=channel&quot;&gt;searching&lt;/a&gt; YouTube Channels for the word “college” or “university.” Literally every major institution of higher education has a Channel. But be warned, this will undoubtedly lead to  a YouTube Spiral&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Microsearch, we love adding to our education by watching these freely available videos. To that end, and to show off the amazing capabilities of our new Video Search product, we decided to create a collection of all the publicly-available videos from each of the Ivy League schools, including Harvard, Yale, Columbia, Brown, Dartmouth, Cornell, Princeton, and UPenn. We thought this would be a cool idea, but we didn’t realize how amazing it really is to have all of that educational content in one place until we put the Video Search site together and started running searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it for yourself. Think of any topic you’d like to learn a little more about, drop it into the search field, and be prepared to spend hours learning from some of the greatest minds of our generation. For example, I’m really interested in the emerging field of “Digital Humanities,” so I ran a quick search and found hundreds of videos on the topic. From there, I tried searching “politics,” “biochemistry,” and “climate change.” In less than a second, Video Search responds with a seemingly endless list of videos to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you click into one of the videos, not only can you watch the whole video right there in the same window, but you can also read the transcript as it scrolls in time with the video. Your search query is highlighted, and you can easily jump between results in the transcript. If you find something you like and want to share, just highlight the transcript and a link is created that jumps right to that spot in the video. You can share it via Facebook, Twitter, or email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are you interested in? Check out the demo below, and let us know what you think in the comments section. Also, what other kinds of video collections would you be interested in seeing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;overflow: hidden; height: 600px; width: 100%;&quot; src=&quot;http://qa5.microsearch.net/IvyLeagueVideo/?q=science&amp;amp;p=0&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><summary type="html">One of the best things about YouTube, in my opinion, is the amount of videos available from colleges and universities around the world. If you haven’t seen this for yourself, I highly recommend searching YouTube Channels for the word “college” or “university.” Literally every major institution of higher education has a Channel. But be warned, this will undoubtedly lead to  a YouTube Spiral&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Video Search by Microsearch, Your Best Defense Against the YouTube Spiral</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/introducing-video-search/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Video Search by Microsearch, Your Best Defense Against the YouTube Spiral" /><published>2017-01-20T13:36:35-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-20T13:36:35-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/introducing-video-search</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/introducing-video-search/">&lt;p&gt;Watching YouTube videos is addictive, but perhaps this goes without saying in 2015. In 2014, during the height of the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9bZkp7q19f0&amp;amp;gl=GB&amp;amp;hl=en-GB&amp;amp;feature=kp&quot;&gt;Gangnam Style&lt;/a&gt;” craze—you remember the music video by South Korean pop star Psy that went viral last year—&lt;i&gt;The Economist &lt;/i&gt;created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2014/06/daily-chart-1&quot;&gt;chart&lt;/a&gt; comparing the time spent watching the video on YouTube to the time it took to build the Empire State Building, the Great Pyramid, and Stonehenge, among others. It turns out, we could have built 20 Empire State Buildings in the time we spent watching Psy dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason that viewers get sucked into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Youtube+Spiral&amp;amp;defid=7618617&quot;&gt;YouTube Spiral&lt;/a&gt; is the ease of clicking on the related videos links to the right of the player. But the reason they lament the time spent clicking and watching videos is because, for the most part, YouTube Spirals don’t lead to any edifying content. Sure, you started out looking for some informational or educational content, but in short time you’re watching cat videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, as a YouTube channel owner, there was a way to ensure that viewers who found your content, would keep watching your content, without being distracted away by the ephemera found in YouTube’s “related” links?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s where &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsearch.net/videosearch/&quot;&gt;Video Search&lt;/a&gt; by Microsearch comes in. The premise is simple: from the content owner’s standpoint, you’ve created and posted dozens of videos, you should benefit from those views. And, from the viewers’ standpoint, they found your content because it was relevant to them; wouldn’t they be better served by finding more of what you offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is precisely what Video Search does. By compiling all of your YouTube videos, making their transcripts fully searchable and shareable, and embedding them on your own website, you can be sure that users will find your content easier, view more of it, and share direct links back to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of just how effective this can be, we used Video Search technology to compile publicly available YouTube videos from each of the Ivy League schools. There are hundreds of videos, all related in the sense that they offer educational content from America’s top universities. With Video Search, you can search them all in one place. You’ll see your search results in context, and when you click the video link it will open to the exact spot where your keyword appears. And, you can just as easily skip to the next video in search results if the current offering doesn’t have what you’re looking for. Check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching YouTube videos doesn’t have to be a waste of time, and as a YouTube channel owner, you shouldn’t have to lose viewers to the latest viral fad. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsearch.net/#contact-form-2&quot;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; with us for more information about how Microsearch’s Video Search product can help make your videos more searchable, shareable, and search engine optimized. And check back here for more useful information and tips on getting the most out of your online videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;overflow: hidden; height: 600px; width: 100%;&quot; src=&quot;http://qa5.microsearch.net/IvyLeagueVideo/?q=science&amp;amp;p=0&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><summary type="html">Watching YouTube videos is addictive, but perhaps this goes without saying in 2015. In 2014, during the height of the “Gangnam Style” craze—you remember the music video by South Korean pop star Psy that went viral last year—The Economist created a chart comparing the time spent watching the video on YouTube to the time it took to build the Empire State Building, the Great Pyramid, and Stonehenge, among others. It turns out, we could have built 20 Empire State Buildings in the time we spent watching Psy dance.</summary></entry></feed>
